Mihkel Lukats

Sestonia, Tallinn

in linkedin.com/in/mihkel-lukats-98677015/

I FAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Lead software engineer with 7+ years of experience in building software and leading customer projects. I focus on creating software that increases business value. That requires close connection with customer and developing software in an agile way.

Core Competencies

- Team Leading
- Web Application Development
- Software Engineering
- Technical Leading
- Test Driven Development

- Mentoring
- Agile Software Development
- Java Development

Projects

• PSD2 Payments

Built microservice to facilitate PSD2 payment flow in client information system.

• Authentication Platform With Multilayered Cryptography

With small team designed, built and deployed successful Alpha on extremely tight schedule.

• Loan Platform

Built core day-change logic; improved loan scheduling; migrated system; launched project to live.

• Bank Saint Petersburg

Helped team to focus on their architectural goals and implementation of best practices.

Social Features for Payments

Implemented highly appreciated social features to payments. Which enabled users to express their emotions when making payments.

• AB Testing And Conversion Analysis

Very successful co-operation with marketing team to increased e-commerce conversion through very quick deployments and customer behavior testing.

Work experience

Lead Software Engineer

2018 - Present

Freelancer

Working as lead developer on client projects that need high quality and quick execution.

Technologies used

- Java, Spring, JDBCTemplate, MyBatis, JPA, Hibernate
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- ShellScript, Python
- Amazon Web Services
- Kafka, RabbitMQ

Software Craftsman 2017 - 2018

Codeborne

Promoted the use of best practices and practiced Extreme Programming.

Technologies used

- Java, Play!, H2, JPA, Hibernate
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- NodelS

Java Developer 2016 - 2017

Pocosys

Technologies used

- Java, MyBatis
- PostgreSQL
- NodeJS
- RabbitMQ

Lead Java Developer

2014 - 2016

ON24 AS

As lead java developer worked very closely with marketing and iterated quickly to find best solutions to increase business value.

Technologies used

- Java, JDBC, Velocity
- Javascript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- Basic, PHP,Shell Script

Education

PyTorch Scholarship Challenge

2018 - 2019

Udacity

Learned how to build models and algorithms using PyTorch

Deep Learning Nanodegree Foundation Program

2017 - 2017

Udacity

This 4 month Nanodegree program students covered basic neural networks, convolutional neural networks, sequence to sequence models, and Generative adversarial neural networks. They also got familiarized with Google's TensorFlow framework.

